Popular searches

Volvo S60Silverado 1500Car Appraiser ToolHonda CR-VLease Deals

1. [Home](https://www.edmunds.com/)
2. [About Us](https://www.edmunds.com/about/)
3. [Privacy Statement](https://www.edmunds.com/about/privacy.html)

Privacy Statement
=================

Print

_Effective Date: June 26, 2024_

See [State Consumer Privacy Rights and Disclosures](#consumer-privacy-disclosures) for additional disclosures about our collection and use of your "Personal Information" and "Personal Data" under applicable state consumer privacy laws and information about submitting privacy requests.

Edmunds.com, Inc. ("Edmunds") is an affiliate of CarMax, Inc. (together with CarMax's other subsidiaries, "CarMax") that operates as a separate business with respect to the handling of your "Personal Information" and "Personal Data." If you would like to exercise your rights with respect to your "Personal Information" or "Personal Data" held by CarMax, please see the [CarMax General Privacy Policy](https://www.carmax.com/privacy-policy).

### Edmunds Automotive Network

The Edmunds Automotive Network consists of the desktop and mobile versions of Edmunds.com and any other website that we identify as a part of the Edmunds Automotive Network; any apps that we offer; and widgets, tools and content that we offer for display on vehicle dealer and other third-party websites.

This Privacy Statement discloses what information we gather on the Edmunds Automotive Network and how we obtain, use, share and manage it. In addition, this Privacy Statement addresses our receipt and use of information that may be "Personal information" or "Personal Data" under state consumer privacy laws, including "Personal Information" and "Personal Data" collected by us from sources other than the Edmunds Automotive Network. With that exception, this Privacy Statement is not applicable to information that we obtain through any of our other business activities or from other sources.

If you have questions or concerns regarding this Privacy Statement, you may contact us through our [Contact Us](https://help.edmunds.com/anonymous_requests/new) form.

### Your Personally Identifiable Information (PII)

We collect information that you voluntarily submit to the Edmunds Automotive Network to receive products and services or related information that you request from either us or companies with which we do business. The information you submit may include your name, address, e-mail address and/or telephone number. We refer to the personally identifiable information that you voluntarily submit to us in response to requests therefor on the Edmunds Automotive Network as your "PII." (Unless we have a street address (or equivalent) for you, we do not consider your city, state or ZIP code to be your PII.)

We also collect information about the devices you use to access the Edmunds Automotive Network as soon as you visit the Edmunds Automotive Network. We do not consider this information to be your PII. However, certain device information may be considered "Personal Information" or "Personal Data" under state consumer privacy laws. See the "State Consumer Privacy Rights and Disclosures" section below for more information.

### Use and Disclosure of Your Personally Identifiable Information (PII)

Your PII may be shared between us and the companies with which we do business, and may also be disclosed to other entities that work with us or those companies to fulfill your request or to offer or provide other products and services to you.

We provide vehicle price quote and inquiry services and dealer communication services, including (i) our CarCode messaging service that enables emails, text and chats between a consumer and either a dealer or an Edmunds service provider, (ii) our vehicle trade-in and appraisal tools displayed on the Edmunds Automotive Network and dealer websites that enable a consumer to find our True Market Value® of a vehicle and that transmit such consumer's PII and that value to the dealer, (iii) dedicated dealer phone numbers displayed on the Edmunds Automotive Network, and (iv) our customer service department which, if a consumer contacts them, may act as an intermediary between such consumer and a dealer (collectively, "Dealer Inquiry and Communication Services").

If you use a Dealer Inquiry and Communication Service, we may use the phone number or email address that you use or provide to obtain or associate additional information about you. We keep copies of email, text and chat communications, and also may make and keep recordings of phone conversations between users of our Dealer Inquiry and Communication Services, including consumers and dealer personnel who communicate through our CarCode messaging service.

The phone number or email you provide; the additional information that we obtain using that information; the email, text and chat communications; and any call recordings may be made available to the dealer, to our services providers and the dealer's service providers to facilitate those communications, to vehicle manufacturers and/or their distributors, agents and contractors, and to any social media website or application from which you initiate a communication.

We may use whatever information we may have or know about you, including your PII, to customize or enhance your experience on the Edmunds Automotive Network (including the display of advertisements) and to provide, or communicate with you concerning, our products or services or those of companies with which we do business. We may use this information to optimize the manner in which the products or services you requested are operated and managed or to optimize the operation and management of other products and services. We may also use this information for purposes of reporting and analytics, including demonstrating to the companies with which we do business the effectiveness of our products and services. We use city, state and ZIP code (which we assign based on your IP address) to display to you information customized for your region.

We may disclose whatever information we may have or know about you, including your PII, without first providing additional notification to you or obtaining your consent: (a) to third-party service providers that provide advice, products or services to us, or that assist us to improve our products, services or information, or to better understand their value to our visitors or to the companies with which we do business or are considering doing business; (b) in connection with any merger or acquisition of Edmunds or a parent company, or any sale or other transfer of assets by Edmunds to another entity; or (c) to other third parties if we determine that disclosure of that information (i) is or may be required by law or legal process, or is requested by a governmental agency, (ii) is or may be reasonably necessary to enforce the Edmunds Automotive Network [Visitor Agreement](https://www.edmunds.com/about/visitor-agreement.html), or to take appropriate action if a visitor or other third party is determined by us to have violated that agreement, or (iii) is or may be reasonably necessary to protect the rights, property or safety of Edmunds or a parent company, the Edmunds Automotive Network, our visitors or other third parties (including, when applicable, consumers, dealers and manufacturers). In addition, we may disclose your PII to social media companies in a "hashed" (i.e., encoded) format that can only be recognized if you have an account with the recipient.

From time to time, we may also receive information requests for, and disclose to third parties, portions of the Edmunds Automotive Network's log files that show which "Internet service provider" a visitor has used or other visitor information; that information may enable third parties to discover, through that Internet service provider, the identity of a visitor.

### Choices About Use and Disclosure of Your Personally Identifiable Information (PII)

In certain locations on the Edmunds Automotive Network where we obtain your PII, we may include a "check box" (or another process) for the purpose of soliciting your consent to receive promotional and marketing communications and/or other information from other entities selected by us. By providing your consent (such as by "checking" the box, or leaving the box "checked"), you are agreeing to receive promotional and marketing communications from those other entities, and you are consenting to our providing your PII to those other entities.

If you no longer wish to receive promotional and marketing communications from us or our partners, you may do so (i) if you received a promotional or marketing email from us, by following the link for that purpose located at the bottom of the email, or (ii) by sending a request to us through our [Contact Us](https://help.edmunds.com/anonymous_requests/new) form. However, withdrawing your consent will not affect the rights of the other entities that previously received your PII to continue to send communications to you and otherwise use your PII, except as otherwise may be required under state consumer privacy law.

If you have registered on Edmunds.com, we may send you certain administrative and service messages in connection with the products and services available to you; you cannot opt out of receiving those communications, except as may be otherwise required under state consumer privacy or other United States law.

See the "State Consumer Privacy Rights and Disclosures" section below for information about your ability to make choices about the use and disclosure of your "Personal Information" and "Personal Data."

### Updating Your PII

If there is a change to any of your PII submitted as a part of registering on Edmunds.com, you may update that information by logging into your profile. If you would like to modify any PII provided to the Edmunds Automotive Network through the use of one of our vehicle price quote or inquiry services, or otherwise, please send a request to us through our [Contact Us](https://help.edmunds.com/anonymous_requests/new) form.

### Your Precise Geolocation Information

When you visit the Edmunds Automotive Network, you may be prompted to provide your permission to our collecting and using your location information.

If you consent, we may use your precise geolocation information to show you nearby inventory, dealers and pricing information. In addition, we may continue to collect and use your precise geolocation information obtained through your use of our mobile site or app, even when the mobile site or app is not open, to notify you when a vehicle that you "saved" or in which you expressed interest is available at a dealer near your current location. We may also use this information for analytics purposes.

You may discontinue collection of geolocation information by changing the app's settings or the location settings on your mobile device.

### Information We Collect Through Cookies and Other Technologies

When you visit the Edmunds Automotive Network, we may place pieces of code, commonly referred to as "cookies," on your computer or other devices you use to access the Edmunds Automotive Network, such as your mobile phone or tablet, or use other technology to collect and retain information about you, such as your IP address and ZIP code, as soon as you visit the Edmunds Automotive Network. We also use cookies and other technology to collect and retain additional information about you, or from activity on devices associated with you, such as your online activities over time on the Edmunds Automotive Network and across third-party websites and online services.

In addition to use for our own internal business purposes described above, we may provide this information to, or share this information with, third parties, including third-party advertisers that display advertising on the Edmunds Automotive Network or third-party websites and online services with which we do business. If you are a resident of California, Virginia or another state that has a consumer privacy law, please see the "State Consumer Privacy Rights and Disclosures" section below for more information.

Edmunds has not implemented a response to browser-based Do Not Track signals, except for the Global Privacy Control as described in the State Consumer Privacy Rights and Disclosures section below. Because of the current lack of consensus with respect to the Do Not Track standard from both a compliance perspective and a technical perspective, we have not yet determined if or how we would implement a response to Do Not Track signals. We will continue to evaluate this in the event a uniform standard is adopted.

Certain browsers may allow you to disable cookies. However, disabling cookies from the Edmunds Automotive Network may prevent you from using various features of the Edmunds Automotive Network.

Please see the "State Consumer Privacy Rights and Disclosures" section below for information about Edmunds' response to Global Privacy Control signals.

### Use of Social Media Accounts

The Edmunds Automotive Network may allow you to log into and associate your social media accounts, including Facebook, Instagram, Twitter, LinkedIn, YouTube and Pinterest, with the Edmunds Automotive Network. By using this functionality, you give the Edmunds Automotive Network permission to access all of the elements of your social media account information that you have made available to be shared, and to use it in accordance with the applicable social network's terms of use.

Your social media privacy settings may enable the Edmunds Automotive Network to retrieve information from your social media accounts, including your usernames, profile photo, the date and time you sent messages using a social media application, and the contents of those messages. Please refer to your social media privacy settings for information about what data is shared with the Edmunds Automotive Network and other connected applications, and to manage the data that is shared through your account (including information about your activities using the Edmunds Automotive Network). If you would like to disconnect a social network account from the Edmunds Automotive Network, please refer to the social media account settings of the applicable social network.

### Surveys

Occasionally we or another company on our behalf may conduct visitor surveys to better target our content to our audience, to improve our products and services, or for the benefit of third parties with which we do business. Accordingly, sometimes the aggregated survey results are shared with our advertisers and other third parties. We never share any survey information about any identified individual with any third party unless that individual consents.

### Our Community Services

The Edmunds Automotive Network provides a number of means by which you may communicate with other visitors and with us. In certain instances, you must first become register on Edmunds.com and/or agree to our [Visitor Agreement](https://www.edmunds.com/about/visitor-agreement.html) in order to add content to the Edmunds Automotive Network through certain services, such as our Forums (the Web's most established automotive message boards) and our Dealer Ratings & Reviews. The [Visitor Agreement](https://www.edmunds.com/about/visitor-agreement.html) sets forth a number of information-sharing and disclosure practices for those services, and accordingly supplements this Privacy Statement. All of your communications made to or through these services are referred to as "Visitor-Submitted Content." For information concerning our use of this and other Visitor-Submitted Content, please see our [Visitor Agreement](https://www.edmunds.com/about/visitor-agreement.html).

### Links to Other Websites

The Edmunds Automotive Network contains links to many other websites and online services not operated by us, including sites where you can obtain automotive products and services. However, this Privacy Statement only applies to the Edmunds Automotive Network and the information we collect thereon, and we are not responsible for the privacy policies or practices of any other websites or online services. For additional information about those links, please review our [Visitor Agreement](https://www.edmunds.com/about/visitor-agreement.html).

### Third-Party Ad Servers and Advertisers

We use third party advertising serving companies to serve advertisements; to provide us with data collection, reporting, ad response measurement and site analytics; and to assist with delivery of relevant marketing messages and advertisements. These third parties may collect information about your online activities over time on the Edmunds Automotive Network and across other websites and online services. These advertising serving companies may use information (not including your name, address, e-mail address, telephone number or other PII) about your visits to the Edmunds Automotive Network in order to provide advertisements on the Edmunds Automotive Network and other websites and online services.

### Self-Regulatory Program for Online Behavioral Advertising

The cross-industry Self-Regulatory Program for Online Behavioral Advertising (the "Program") was developed by leading industry associations to apply consumer-friendly standards to online behavioral advertising across the Internet. Edmunds has elected to implement the Program.

The Program applies to "online behavioral advertising," which is defined as the collection of data online from a particular computer or device regarding Web viewing behaviors over time, and across non-affiliate websites, for the purpose of using that data to predict visitor preferences or interests to deliver advertising to that computer or device based on the preferences or interests inferred from those Web viewing behaviors. (The Program does not apply to a website's collection of viewing behavior solely for its own uses, or to "contextual advertising" that delivers advertisements based on the content of a Web page, a search query or a visitor's contemporaneous behavior on a website.)

Our advertisers may from time to time use data collected about your visits to the Edmunds Automotive Network and other websites to target ads to you on the Edmunds Automotive Network and other websites and online services.

In addition, the Edmunds Automotive Network may from time to time permit third parties to collect non-personally identifiable website usage information about our visitors for the purpose of facilitating the serving of targeted ads on other websites and online services. To do this, we permit those third parties to place and use cookies on the browsers of our visitors, and use Web beacons and other tracking technologies on the Edmunds Automotive Network. These third parties may also use personally identifiable information obtained from other sources to serve advertisements over time and across websites and online services.

Other companies' use of information collected through their cookies and other tracking technologies is subject to their own privacy policies and not this one. To learn more about your choices and how to opt out from receiving the types of ads described above, please [click here](http://www.aboutads.info/choices/) or paste [http://www.aboutads.info/choices/](http://www.aboutads.info/choices/) into your internet browser.

You may also opt out of tracking and receiving the types of ads described above on your mobile device by some mobile advertising companies and similar entities by modifying your device settings or downloading the App Choices app at [www.aboutads.info/appchoices](http://www.aboutads.info/appchoices).

### Security

The security of your personal information is important to us. We follow generally accepted industry standards to protect your Personal Information, both during transmission to us and once we receive it. However, no method of transmission over the Internet, or method of electronic storage, is 100% secure. If you have any questions about security on the Edmunds Automotive Network, please use our [Contact Us](https://help.edmunds.com/anonymous_requests/new) form.

### Privacy of EU Residents

The Edmunds Automotive Network provides products and services related to vehicles offered for sale or lease in the United States. We do not knowingly collect or solicit personal data from anyone resident in the European Union or knowingly allow those persons to use our products or services. If you are an EU resident, please do not visit the Edmunds Automotive Network or use any of its products and services. In the event that we obtain actual knowledge that we have collected personal data from an EU resident, we will work to delete that data promptly. If you believe that we might have any information from or about an EU resident, please contact us through our [Contact Us](https://help.edmunds.com/anonymous_requests/new) form.

### Children's Privacy

The Edmunds Automotive Network is a general audience site not directed at children under the age of 16. We do not knowingly collect or solicit personal information from anyone under the age of 16 or knowingly allow those persons to use our products and services. If you are under 16, please do not visit the Edmunds Automotive Network or use any of its products and services. In the event that we obtain actual knowledge that we have collected personal information from a child under age 16, we will delete that information as quickly as possible. If you believe that we might have any information from or about a child under 16, please contact us through our [Contact Us](https://help.edmunds.com/anonymous_requests/new) form.

### State Consumer Privacy Rights and Disclosures

Consumers (defined below) may request to opt-out from the sale and sharing of their Personal Information (defined below) at [Do Not Sell or Share My Personal Information](https://www.edmunds.com/data-privacy-request/) or paste [https://www.edmunds.com/data-privacy-request](https://www.edmunds.com/data-privacy-request/) into your internet browser.

This Privacy Statement does not apply to the "Personal Information" (as that term is defined under California Consumer Privacy Act as modified by the California Privacy Rights Act) collected about current or former Edmunds' job applicants, employees and individual contractors. For information about Edmunds' collection, use and disclosure of that Personal Information, please see the Edmunds.com, Inc. Careers Privacy Statement posted on the Edmunds Intranet Roadside Assistance page or email [data-privacy-requests@edmunds.com](mailto:data-privacy-requests@edmunds.com) to request a copy.

The following definitions are used in this section of this Privacy Statement:

"Consumer" means a resident of a Covered State (defined below).

"Covered States" means California, Virginia, Colorado and Connecticut, and (ii) effective December 31, 2023, Utah.

"Dealers" means the new and used vehicle dealers.

"Deidentified Information" means Personal Information that has been "Deidentified," as that term is defined under (i) the California Consumer Privacy Act as modified by the California Privacy Rights Act, and (ii) other Covered States' consumer privacy laws.

"Dealer Inquiry and Communication Services" shall have the meaning given to it in the "Use and Disclosure of Your Personally Identifiable Information (PII)" section above.

"Edmunds Automotive Network" has the meaning given to it in the "Edmunds Automotive Network" section above.

"Manufacturers" means the companies that manufacture and/or distribute vehicles, and their affiliates, agents and contractors and service providers).

"Personal Information" of a Consumer means the Consumer's (i) "Personal Information," as that term is defined under California Consumer Privacy Act as modified by the California Privacy Rights Act, and (ii) "Personal Data," as that term is defined under other Covered States' consumer privacy laws.

State Consumer Privacy Rights

Subject to certain limits under the laws of the Covered States, Consumers have these rights:

* Right to opt-out of certain disclosures: Consumers may request that their Personal Information not be sold or shared for cross context behavioral advertising by Edmunds (an "Opt-Out Request").  

* Right to deletion: Consumers may request that their Personal Information be deleted by Edmunds (a "Deletion Request"); however, Edmunds is permitted to retain certain Personal Information for certain purposes.  

* Right to correction: Consumers may request that incorrect Personal Information maintained by Edmunds be corrected (a "Correction Request").  

* Right to reporting and access: Consumers may request Edmunds to provide reporting about our collection and handling of their Personal Information (a "Reporting Request) and/or copies of specific pieces of their Personal Information maintained by Edmunds (a "Copy of Personal Information Request") in a readily useable format.  

* Right to appeal: Consumers may appeal Edmunds' denial of, or inaction regarding, their privacy request (an "Appeal Request").

Edmunds does not collect or use Sensitive Personal Information (defined below) for purposes outside of those permitted by applicable law, including not to infer a Consumer's characteristics. Accordingly, Edmunds does not provide for requests to limit use of Sensitive Personal Information.

Edmunds will not discriminate against any Consumer because that Consumer exercised any of his or her rights under a Covered State's consumer privacy laws.

Privacy Request Submission and Verification

Requests may be submitted online at [www.edmunds.com/data-privacy-request](https://www.edmunds.com/data-privacy-request/) or by phone at 855-585-2033. In addition, Consumers may submit an Opt-Out Request by clicking on the "Do Not Sell or Share My Personal Information" link on the Edmunds.com website or on the screen of Edmunds' mobile app where Edmunds links to this Privacy Statement. Note that Opt-Out Requests submitted by phone cannot be implemented for Internet Activity Data (defined below). If you want your Opt-Out Request to apply to your Internet Activity Data, you need to submit your request online at [www.edmunds.com/data-privacy-request](https://www.edmunds.com/data-privacy-request/) or through the "Do Not Sell or Share My Personal Information" link.

You can also submit an Opt-Out Request that will apply to Internet Activity Data by visiting our website using a browser that transmits the Global Privacy Control signal. If you do so, we will store an opt-out cookie on that browser. The opt-out cookie is specific to the device and browser you are using when the Global Privacy Control signal is enabled. If you visit our website using another device or browser for which you have not previously submitted an Opt-Out Request, or if you clear the cookies on a browser that you previously used to submit your Opt-Out Request, we will not be able to recognize your opt-out preferences.

In order for Edmunds to be able to verify and process a privacy request, it must contain all of the following information:

* The type of privacy request.  

* The Consumer's first and last name, email address, phone number and full street address (including ZIP code).  

* For Correction Requests, a description of the incorrect Personal Information and the corrected Personal Information. If the incorrect Personal Information was discovered due to a prior privacy request, the request should also reference to that prior request, including the request type and submission date.  

* For Appeal Requests, the reason for the appeal and reference the prior request that is the subject of the appeal, including the request type and submission date.

Consumers may designate an "Authorized Agent" to submit privacy requests on their behalf. If a request is submitted by a Consumer's Authorized Agent, the request must also contain the Authorized Agent's first and last name, email address, phone number and full street address. The Consumer or Authorized Agent must also provide Edmunds with a copy of a (a) valid power of attorney, or (b) written permission signed by the Consumer demonstrating that the Authorized Agent has been authorized by the Consumer to act on his/her behalf for privacy requests. A scanned copy of the power of attorney or signed written permission should be sent to [data-privacy-requests@edmunds.com](mailto:data-privacy-requests@edmunds.com). If the Consumer or Authorized Agent prefers to send Edmunds a copy via U.S. Mail, he or she should send an email asking for mailing instructions to Edmunds at [data-privacy-requests@edmunds.com](mailto:data-privacy-requests@edmunds.com).

In order for Edmunds to verify privacy requests:

* For a Deletion, Reporting or Copy of Personal Information Request, the Consumer must verify the request by responding to the messages sent to the Consumer's email and phone number. Note that mobile phone numbers will receive a text message and landlines will receive a voicemail message.  

* If a Correction or Appeal Request, the Consumer will need to respond to the messages sent to the Consumer's email and phone number or, if requested by us, complete a different verification method or provide additional information (which we will use to verify the request).  

* Edmunds will need to be able to find in its databases at least two of the following items of the Consumer's Personal Information contained in the request: name (first and last), email address and phone number.  

* For requests submitted by an Authorized Agent, Edmunds must also receive (a) valid power of attorney, or (b) written permission signed by the Consumer demonstrating that the Authorized Agent has been authorized by the Consumer to act on his/her behalf for privacy requests; and the Consumer's and Authorized Agent's names and other information submitted with the request must match the information in the power of attorney or written permission.

Collection, Use and Transfer of Personal Information

Edmunds does not knowingly collect, receive, disclose, share or sell any data about individuals under 16 years of age. See the "Children's Privacy" section above.

Edmunds collects and/or receives the categories of Personal Information described below.

* User-Provided Identifiers: Edmunds may collect or receive the identifiers (such as your real name, account IDs and usernames, street and email addresses, phone numbers, social security number, driver's license number, birthdate and gender and your vehicle's license plate number or vehicle identification number) that you voluntarily submit to Edmunds, including through the Edmunds Automotive Network, to Edmunds' editorial and customer service departments, and through Edmunds' products and services used or implemented by third party websites and applications. User-Provided Identifiers also includes any identifiers that you may include in your responses to any survey Edmunds requests. If you use one of Edmunds' Dealer Inquiry and Communication Services, Edmunds collects (i) your phone number and/or email address that you used or provided, and (ii) any other identifiers that may be contained in (a) any recording of your conversation that may be made, or (b) your email, text or chat communications. Edmunds refers to the foregoing identifiers as "User-Provided Identifiers."  

* Associated Identifiers: If you contact Edmunds' customer service department by phone, or use an Edmunds' Dealer Inquiry and Communication Service to call, or to email, text or chat through your mobile device, when Edmunds obtains your phone number Edmunds may use it to obtain your name from a data provider. In addition, when you log into or associate one of your social media accounts with the Edmunds Automotive Network, you allow Edmunds to access all of the elements of that social media account that you have made available to be shared (such as account IDs, user tokens, usernames, profile photos and any Personal Information that may be contained in the message you send using that social media account). Edmunds refers to the foregoing identifiers as "Associated Identifiers."  

* Third-Party-Provided Identifiers: Edmunds receives vehicle sales transaction data from certain Dealers and data aggregators that may contain the identifiers (such as first and last name, street and/or email address, phone number and birth date) of individuals who purchase and lease vehicles (and, if applicable, co-signers for loans and leases) and the vehicle identification number of the vehicle purchased or leased. Edmunds refers to the foregoing identifiers as "Third-Party-Provided Identifiers."  

* Credit Information: When you use an Edmunds product or service to calculate or obtain an estimated lease or loan payment, Edmunds collects your self-reported credit score and the credit reporting agency's transaction ID, which is used by Edmunds to obtain your FICO score. Edmunds refers to the foregoing information as "Credit Information."  

* Precise Geolocation Data: When you visit the Edmunds Automotive Network, you may be prompted to provide your permission to our collecting and using your location information. If you consent, we collect your precise geolocation information. Edmunds refers to the foregoing data as "Precise Geolocation Data."  

* Internet Activity Data: Upon the commencement of your visit to or use of the Edmunds Automotive Network, when technically possible Edmunds, and Facebook and certain other third parties who are permitted by Edmunds, (i) collect your Internet Protocol (IP) address and information about the device you are using to access the Edmunds Automotive Network, and (ii) place pieces of code (commonly referred to as "cookies") on that device or use other technologies to collect and retain information about you, or from activity on devices associated with you, such as your online activities over time on the Edmunds Automotive Network and across third-party websites and online services. When you visit the website of a dealer with which Edmunds does business, Edmunds, our service providers and Facebook collect the fact that you have visited that website. Edmunds refers to the foregoing information as "Internet Activity Data." For information about Facebook's use of the information it collects from the Edmunds Automotive Network and the submission of privacy requests to Facebook, see [https://www.facebook.com/privacy/policies/uso/](https://www.facebook.com/privacy/policies/uso/).  

* Professional Information: If Edmunds communicates with you in your capacity as an employee or other representative of a business (such as a dealer, OEM, agency or vendor), Edmunds may collect your professional contact information, including your name, title, phone number, street and email address, and name of your employer or the business you represent. Edmunds refers to the foregoing as "Professional Information."  

* Recordings and Messages: If consumers or dealer personnel use an Edmunds' Dealer Inquiry and Communication Service, we keep copies of email, text and chat communications and may make and keep recording of calls. Edmunds refers to the foregoing as "Recordings and Messages."  

* Sensitive Personal Information: Your account log-ins, passwords, government identifiers and your Precise Geolocation Data are considered "Sensitive Personal Information." If you use an Edmunds’ Dealer Inquiry and Communication Service, your emails, texts, chats and call recordings may be considered "Sensitive Personal Information."

Edmunds uses, discloses, shares or "sells" Personal Information as set forth below. To opt-out of the sharing of Personal Information for cross context behavioral advertising or sales of Personal Information, please click [Do Not Sell or Share My Personal Information](https://www.edmunds.com/data-privacy-request/).

* Except as otherwise set forth below, Edmunds uses all categories of Personal Information:

* To provide products and services to you and customize or enhance your experience on the Edmunds Automotive Network (including the display of advertisements);
* To evaluate, analyze, optimize, enhance and change Edmunds' products and services, and to develop new ones;
* To help detect fraudulent activity, identify and repair errors, and help to ensure the security and integrity of Edmunds' products, services and systems; and
* For reporting and analytics purposes, including demonstrating to the companies with which Edmunds does business the effectiveness of Edmunds' products and services  

* Edmunds uses all categories of Personal Information other than Sensitive Personal Information to communicate with you concerning Edmunds' products and services and those of third parties with which Edmunds does business, and to send you promotional and marketing communications.  

* If you have registered on Edmunds.com, Edmunds may use your User-Provided and Associated Identifiers to send you messages in connection with the products and services available to you.  

* Edmunds uses your IP address to determine your city, state and ZIP code in order to display to you information customized for your region. Edmunds may use Precise Geolocation Data to show you nearby inventory, Dealers and pricing information, and Edmunds may use it to notify you when a vehicle that you "saved" or in which you expressed interest is available at a dealer near your current location. Edmunds may also use this information for analytics and reporting purposes.  

* Edmunds uses User-Provided, Associated and Third-Party-Provided Identifiers to determine if the visitor communications submitted through an Edmunds' Dealer Inquiry and Communication Service resulted in vehicle sales and for other analytics and reporting purposes.  

* Edmunds uses Internet Activity Data that Edmunds collects on the Edmunds Automotive Network to serve advertising to you both on and off the Edmunds Automotive Network. Edmunds uses Internet Activity Data it collects on a dealer website for reporting and analytics purposes, including demonstrating to that dealer the effectiveness of Edmunds' products and services.  

* Edmunds uses your Credit Information only to provide products and services to you, to calculate customized vehicle lease or loan payments for you for a vehicle that you have selected, and to advise the dealer offering that vehicle that you qualify for those lease or payment terms.  

* To the extent that Edmunds maintains Deidentified Information, Edmunds commits to maintain and use that information in a deidentified form and not reidentify it, except as may be allowed by law.  

* Edmunds may disclose all categories of Personal information:  

* To service providers with which Edmunds contracts to provide services to us and that need to use and process such Personal Information in order to provide such services;
* To Dealers and Manufacturers (with which Edmunds does business or is considering doing business);
* To actual or potential counterparties, and their representatives, counsel, advisors and agents, in connection with any merger by, or acquisition of, Edmunds or a parent company, or any sale or other transfer of assets by Edmunds or a parent company to another entity; and
* To law enforcement; governmental entities; Edmunds' representatives, counsel, advisors and agents; and other third parties if Edmunds determines that disclosure of that information (i) is or may be required by law or legal process, or is requested by law enforcement or a governmental agency, (ii) is or may be reasonably necessary to enforce the Edmunds Automotive Network [Visitor Agreement](https://www.edmunds.com/about/visitor-agreement.html), or to take appropriate action if a visitor or other third party is determined by us to have violated that agreement, or (iii) is or may be reasonably necessary to protect the rights, property or safety of Edmunds or its parent company, the Edmunds Automotive Network, Edmunds' visitors or other third parties (including, when applicable, Consumers or Dealers)  

* Edmunds discloses User-Provided and Associated Identifiers to the Dealers whom you have selected or have vehicles that you have specified. In some instances, Edmunds also sends User-Provided and Associated Identifiers to Manufacturers who granted franchises to those Dealers and/or those Manufacturers' contractors and agencies. This disclosure may be considered a "sale" under the laws of California and certain other Covered States' laws.  

* Edmunds may also disclose User-Provided Identifiers to service providers that work with us to fulfill requests you submit to us, to facilitate communications between Consumers and Dealers, or provide other products and services, and to social media companies in a "hashed" (i.e., encoded) format that can only be recognized if you have an account with the recipient. The disclosure to social media companies may be considered a "sale" under the laws of California and certain other Covered States laws even though we do not receive any monetary compensation from the social media companies in return for the information disclosed.  

* In addition, when you log into or associate one of your social media accounts with an Edmunds' Dealer Inquiry and Communication Service, Edmunds discloses certain User-Provided and Associated Identifiers to the social media provider of that account, and the dealer or consumer with which you are communicating may have access to those identifiers.  

* Edmunds discloses Internet Activity Data to Manufacturers for advertising purposes, to social networks for purposes of facilitating advertising on their platforms, to companies that place advertising on third party websites on behalf of Edmunds or its clients, and to companies who display advertising and/or provide targeted internet audience data and/or other services to advertisers or to companies that display advertising. Edmunds may disclose Internet Activity Data (together with User-Provided Identifiers) to companies that use that data to provide their own services to Dealers and Manufacturers. Edmunds may also allow a vendor to collect Internet Activity Data to provide analytics services to Edmunds. The disclosures described above may be considered "sales" under California and other states' laws.  

* When you use Edmunds to obtain offers from third parties to purchase your vehicle, Edmunds sends your User-Provided Identifiers to the Dealers that make those offers and/or companies that obtain those offers from Dealers. When you use Edmunds to estimate the trade-in or sale value of your vehicle, Edmunds may also send your User-Provided Identifiers to Dealers who may be interested in your vehicle and this disclosure may be considered a "sale" or sharing for cross context behavioral advertising under California and certain other states' laws.  

* When you use an Edmunds product or service to calculate or obtain from Edmunds your estimated lease or loan payments for a vehicle offered by a Dealer for sale or lease -- and if you consent -- Edmunds transmits your Credit Information to a company that uses that information to obtain additional information about your credit from a credit reporting agency, which then sends Edmunds a transaction ID that allows Edmunds to collect your FICO score. The credit reporting agency may make available to the Dealer offering that vehicle your FICO score and other credit information. In addition, Edmunds may disclose to that Dealer your self-reported approximate credit score, FICO score and estimated payment terms and may also advise that dealer either that Edmunds believes that you prequalify for those payment terms for that vehicle or that Edmunds did not have sufficient information to determine if you prequalify.

We retain the Personal Information we collect for as long as reasonably necessary to achieve the purposes disclosed at the point of collection or in this Privacy Statement or for other business purposes, unless a shorter or longer retention period is required by law or contract. The length of retention may vary depending upon factors such as:

* The existence of an ongoing relationship between you and us;
* Recordkeeping or legal compliance requirements;
* Service, product and network security and integrity purposes; and
* The need to resolve inquiries or complaints

The following metrics are for the verifiable requests submitted by California Consumers during calendar year 2023:

* Requests to opt-out: 97 received and complied with in whole or in part
* Requests to delete: 7 received and complied with in whole or in part, and 19 received and denied due to not being verifiable
* Requests to know: 2 received and complied with in whole or in part, and 5 received and denied due to not being verifiable
* Requests for correction: 0 received
* Average days to respond: 3.1 days

If you have questions or concerns about Edmunds' privacy policies and practices, please email [GeneralCounsel@edmunds.com](mailto:GeneralCounsel@edmunds.com).

### Changes to this Privacy Statement

We reserve the right, in our sole discretion and at any time, to change this Privacy Statement. Changes will be effective when made and the updated Privacy Statement is posted on the Edmunds Automotive Network; provided, however, that (i) information collected prior to the time any change is posted will be used according to the provisions of this Privacy Statement that applied at the time the information was collected, and (ii) no such change shall be applicable to any dispute between you and us that arises prior to the time such change is effective. If we make material changes to this Privacy Policy that increase our rights to your Personal Information we have previously collected, we will obtain your consent either through an email to your email address or by prominent posting on the Edmunds Automotive Network.

Edmunds Universe

Follow us:

* * *

Edmunds HQ | By the Numbers

[

Company Profile and History](https://www.edmunds.com/about/profile.html)

More on Edmunds

* [
    
    Car Reviews](https://www.edmunds.com/car-reviews/)
* [
    
    New Car Ratings](https://www.edmunds.com/new-car-ratings/)
* [
    
    Compare Popular Vehicles](https://www.edmunds.com/car-reviews/popular-car-comparisons.html)
* [
    
    Best Cars, Trucks & SUVs](https://www.edmunds.com/best-cars/)
* [
    
    Most Researched Vehicles](https://www.edmunds.com/car-reviews/consumers-most-popular.html)
* [
    
    Car Finder](https://www.edmunds.com/finder/car-finder-results.html)

Join Edmunds
------------

Receive pricing updates, shopping tips & more!

Email Address

Sign Up

Follow Us
---------

Download the Edmunds app
------------------------

[© Edmunds.com, Inc.](https://www.edmunds.com/), a wholly owned subsidiary of CarMax, Inc. By using edmunds.com, you consent to the monitoring and storing of your interactions with the website, including by an Edmunds vendor, for use in improving and personalizing our services. See our [Privacy Statement](https://www.edmunds.com/about/privacy.html) for details.
